# Sally R. Perez

sally.perez@gmail.com | (206) 371-2958 | Seattle, WA linkedin.com/in/sallyrperez/ | github.com/SeattleSal | seattlesal.github.io/Portfolio/

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full Stack Web developer with problem-solving mindset and passion to continuously learn new skills. Recently earned Certificate in Full Stack Web Development from University of Washington. Formerly experienced Technology Auditor so I enjoy continuous learning and am ready to move beyond the focus on analysis to creating valuable solutions.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Javascript, Node JS, Express, jQuery, React JS, JSX, MongoDB, Mongoose, MySQL, Sequelize, Bootstrap, Handlebars, HTML 5, CSS, Heroku

#### **PROJECTS**

**Neighborhood Cup-O-Sugar | GitHub:** github.com/bfourGitHub/cup-o-sugar | **Deployed:** neighborhood-cup-o-sugar.herokuapp.com/

**Summary:** A hyper-local sharing experience for users to give and get free items from neighbors.

**Role:** Created database models and backend API calls. Integrated with Cloudinary for photo uploads and displays.

**Tools:** Javascript, Node, Express, Axios, Bcrypt, passport, mongoose, multer, React, Bootstrap, React-Bootstrap, Cloudinary 3P API

**Feast with Friends | GitHub:** github.com/SeattleSal/feast-with-friends | **Deployed:** feast-with-friends-plus.herokuapp.com/

**Summary:** Recommends a list of restaurants that matches the users' dietary restrictions & specified location. **Role:** Created mysql models, controllers, back end apis, integration with yelp API, and helped with handlebars. **Tools:** Javascript, Node, axios, benefit, passpert, handlebars, mysql, sequelize, Yelp 3P, API.

Tools: Javascript, Node, axios, bcrypt, passport, handlebars, mysql, sequelize, Yelp 3P API

**Trail Chasers | GitHub:** github.com/TaaniBravo/Trail-Chaser-Hiking-App | **Deployed:** taanibravo.github.io/Trail-Chaser-Hiking-App/

Summary: Find hikes based on location, length and difficulty.

**Role:** Created search and results page using javascript and bulma, made 3P API calls for trail data and google maps data.

**Tools:** Javascript, Bulma, Trails and Google Maps 3P APIs

### **EXPERIENCE**

Senior Manager Tech Audit | Tech Audit Manager, Amazon, Seattle, WA, January 2017 - March 2020 Led audit portfolio for Devices, Alexa and Digital Content spaces by performing risk analysis and determine prioritization of planned projects. Performed end-to-end audit projects over new products, technologies, services and processes in the areas of Devices, Alexa, Music, Advertising and InfoSec. Reduced security and process gaps by testing setup of Amazon Web Services (AWS) Identity and Access Management and S3 services.

## Senior IT Audit Manager, Outerwall, Bellevue, WA, November 2015 – October 2016

Reduced reliance on outsourcing by establishing in house IT Audit function. Ensured compliance by supporting SOX IT work and executing risk-based technology audits. Established quality assurance improvement program for Internal Audit activities.

## IT Audit Principal, Nordstrom, Seattle, WA, April 2013 – November 2015

Formed two-year Privacy audit program based on Generally Accepted Privacy Principles that identified gaps and improvement areas in handling of third-party vendors. Executed IT risk assessment and audits over Nordstrom Federal Savings Bank (NFSB) technology environment incorporating guidance from FFIEC IT Handbooks. Established guality assurance improvement program for Internal Audit activities.

# Sally R. Perez

sally.perez@gmail.com | (206) 371-2958 | Seattle, WA linkedin.com/in/sallyrperez/ | aithub.com/SeattleSal | seattlesal.aithub.io/Portfolio/

Audit Manager | IT Audit Project Manager, Starbucks, Seattle, WA, May 2006 – March 2013

Provided support and guidance for four direct reports and other team members on projects including compliance audits, operational/financial/IT audits and risk assessments. Coordinated reviews in multiple international licensed and joint-venture markets. Created system implementation controls self-assessment checklist to proactively address upcoming system implementation reviews, scope future audits and communicate risks with IT stakeholders.

# Key Achievements:

- Headed the planning, execution and coordination of a pre-implementation audit review of the largest software implementation in the history of Starbucks at the time. Communicated issues and addressed concerns to external audit team and created communication for executives including the CIO, CFO and Audit Committee.
- Provided technical support and subject matter expertise of third party audit software for Internal Audit
  department. Advised on technical issues and troubleshooting, acted as liaison with IT to roll out installation
  of new modules, functionality setting and upgrades.

## **ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE**

IT Security Advisor, Boeing, Seattle, WA

IT Generalist, Boeing, Seattle, WA

### **EDUCATION**

Full Stack Web Development Certificate, University of Washington, Seattle, WA | March 2021

A 24 week intensive boot camp program focused on gaining technical programming and market-driven skills in Node.js, Express, JavaScript, jQuery, React.js, React, JSX, GitHub, MySQL, MongoDB, Mongoose, Handlebars, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, APIs, Heroku, AJAX, Restful API, ES6, React Hooks, JSON, Sequelize.

Bachelor's in Computer Science, Arizona State University, Tempe, AZ, Graduated Magna Cum Laude